JUAN DAVID MARTÍNEZ RÍOS

CONTACT

- **J** +573178318863
- tinrios3@gmail.com
- Cra 26 #57-23, Palmira, Valle del Cauca 763532 Colombia

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

 I am a software engineer with more than 4 years of coding experience and development process experience. With success in all phases of the development process, design, construction and testing. Work collaboratively and freelance within cross-functional teams to identify and resolve bugs and functionality issues.
 Strong technical analysis skills and development processes.

SKILLS

- Flutter
- Angular
- ReactJs
- NodeJs
- java Spring Boot
- Firebase
- ASP.NET core
- PHP
- TypeScript
- AWS
- OracleDB

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan 2021 - Current

Patagonian, Cali, Valle del Cauca Colombia

- Designed, developed, and deployed software to meet business needs.
- Debugged applications to resolve logical and programming issues.
- Implemented Agile principles to successfully track deliverables and boost development productivity.
- Plan and develop multi platform mobile apps using technologies such as Flutter, Python, CircleCI, Jira, Docker according to the guidelines proposed by the company

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

tyba, Remote, Colombia

- Modified and created customized and standard applications in line with software engineering best practices and standards.
- Automated, maintained and optimized systems and software infrastructure for clients.
- Reviewed software documentation to verify technical accuracy and compliance or completeness.
- Planned and developed multi platform applications using technologies such as Flutter, NodeJS, Firebase, AWS according to the guidelines proposed by the company.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Mar 2021 - Aug 2022

Moove-it, Cali, Colombia

- Developed program logic for new applications based on fresh coding or revamped logic from existing applications.
- Applied feedback from code review and implemented changes to meet standards.
- Coded, tested, debugged, documented, and implemented web software applications.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb 2020 - Apr 2021

Sama Technologies SAS, Remote

- Debugged applications to resolve logical and programming issues.
- Designed, developed, and deployed software to meet business needs.
- Plan and develop multi platform mobile applications using technologies such as Flutter, NodeJs, Firebase, AWS according to the guidelines proposed by the company.

SEMI SR MOBILE DEVELOPER Mar 2020 - Feb 2021

Bess2biz, Remote

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Performed technical analysis to determine best ways to meet functional objectives.

- PostgreSql
- Docker
- Codemagic CI/CD
- Azure

 Lead the mobile area and coordinate remote team in USA, developing together with my development team multi platform mobile applications (FLUTTER) that integrate API Rest - NodeJs/ MongoDB and Angular with blockchain and Firebase.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2019 - Feb 2020

Squareball Studios, Cali, Valle del Cauca Colombia

- Designed, developed, and deployed software to meet business needs.
- Develop, lead and implement pertinent and effective systematic solutions to solve problems of great impact for the company, all applied in soft product technologies such as web and administrative mobile applications. Manipulation of crowded databases for sustainability and better performance on high-end platforms using technologies such as ANGULAR, Xamarin, Flutter, ASP.NET CORE, MySql, Firebase.

SOFTWARE ANALYST DEVELOPER Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

GTC SAS, Cali, Valle del Cauca Colombia

- Integrated, developed, and designed software solutions based on business objectives and requirements.
- Develop and implement relevant and effective systematic solutions to solve problems of great impact for the company, all this applied in soft product technologies such as accounting and administrative web applications. Manipulation of crowded databases to provide support and better performance on high-level platforms.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ANALYST - COMPUTER SCIENCE Oct 2018

Industrial Biotechnology Center - SENA., Palmira, Valle del Cauca Colombia

- GPA 4.5
- · Graduated with distinction.
- Volunteer, Sennova research and innovation project for the fruit and vegetable trade through a mobile application (SENA 2018).

SYSTEMS ENGINEER - COMPUTER SCIENCE Dec 2016
University - Antonio Jose Camacho, Cali, Valle del Cauca Colombia

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA - COMPUTER SCIENCE Dec 2014

College Jorge Isaacs, El Cerrito, Valle del Cauca Colombia